{
  "name": "Orthopedic cards",
  "cards": [
    { "front": "Dorsal rim fracture of the radius.", "back": "Barton's Fracture" },
    { "front": "Trimalleolar ankle fracture of the distal tibia (medial, lateral, and posterior articular margin or posterior malleolus of the tibia)", "back": "Cotton's Fracture" },
    { "front": "Fractures of the radius with ulna that may involve the wrist joint; caused bu extending the outstreached hand", "back": "Colle's fracture" },
    { "front": "Double fracture of the pelvic ring, causing instability of the pelvis", "back": "Malgaigne's fracture" },
    { "front": "Fracture of the distal third of the radius with associated radioulnar dislocation", "back": "Galeazzi's fracture" },
    { "front": "Fracture of the shaft of the ulna with displacement of fragments", "back": "Moonreggia's fracture" },
    { "front": "Fracture at the base of associated subluxation of dislocation of the metacarpal joint of the thumb", "back": "Bennett's fracture" },
    { "front": "Fracture of the fibula including malleoli of the ankle", "back": "Pott's fracture" },
    { "front": "Shoulder and humeral displaced fracture resulting in three or more fragments", "back": "Neer fracture" },
    { "front": "Compressiuon fractureo fthe body of a cervical vertebra with separation of a bone fracgment", "back": "Teardrop fracture" },
    { "front": "Is the act of pulling and drawing which is associated iwth counter traction", "back": "Traction" },
    { "front": "Traction equipments", "back": "Thomas splint, Pearson attachment, Rest splint, Cord sash, safety pins or clips, Slings(2 sizes), Foot rest, weights" },
    { "front": "What are short traction equipments for?", "back": "for teh thigh" },
    { "front": "What are longer traction equipments for?", "back": "for the traction" },
    { "front": "What are the longest traction equipments for?", "back": "for the suspension" },
    { "front": "Parts of the Balkan frame orthopedic bed", "back": "Horizontal Bars, Clamps, 1 diagonal bar, Overhead Trapeze, Pulleys, 4 Vertical bars, Firm Mattress, Crossbar, Fracture board, Shock blocks" },
    { "front": "what is the Elisarov external fixator for?", "back": "Comminuted Fracture = non healing" },
    { "front": "what is the Delata frame external fixator for?", "back": "Fracture of Tibia Fibula" },
    { "front": "what is the Halo vest Traction for?", "back": "Cervical affection" },
    { "front": "what is the hybrid external fixator for?", "back": "Fracture of tibia Fibula, ankle and knee" },
    { "front": "what is the Kirsneir's Wire with holder for?", "back": "Balance skeletal traction for pediatric patients" },
    { "front": "what is the Steinmann pin with holder for?", "back": "Balance skeletal traction for adult patients" },
    { "front": "what is the Orthopix for?", "back": "Fracture of long bone" },
    { "front": "what is the Roger Angerson External fixator for?", "back": "Comminuted fracture for long bones, lower extremity" },
    { "front": "what is the Russel-taylor interlocking nail system for?", "back": "provides rigid intramedullary fixation for long bone fractures" },
    { "front": "what is the Spanning external fixator for?", "back": "Patellar fracture" },
    { "front": "what is the Active lock for?", "back": "Modular hip system" },
    { "front": "what is the Intramedullar locking screw for?", "back": "Femular dracture, M/3rd" },
    { "front": "what is the Spacer: Antibiotic for?", "back": "Replacement for infected presthesis" },
    { "front": "what is the Subluminar wiring for?", "back": "Spine" },
    { "front": "what is the Antibiotic beads for?", "back": "Post-op medication for Osteomyelitis" },
    { "front": "what is the Endoprosthesis for hemarthroplasty for?", "back": "Partial hip hemiarthroplasty, Femur and Neck of Femur" },
    { "front": "Intermedullary Nail, (all)", "back": "AO, Grosse Kempf interlocked, AO universal, Recon, Russel-Taylor Interlocked, Kuntscher, Schnieder, Broker Wells, Williams(Kutscher) Y-Nail" },
    { "front": "what is the Luque rod for?", "back": "Intermedullary Nail for small long bones" },
    { "front": "what is the Bone plate for?", "back": "used in bones such as the radius or ulna" },
    { "front": "what is the T-Plate or Buttress plate for?", "back": "FX of D/Tibia" },
    { "front": "what is the Spine rod pedicular scress foxator for?", "back": "Internal immorbalizer" },
    { "front": "what is the mini Raef for?", "back": "Comminuted carpal and meracarpal" },
    { "front": "what is the Bootleg traction for?", "back": "post-op w/ residual paralysis" },
    { "front": "what is the Bryant Skin traction for?", "back": "Congenital hip dislocation" },
    { "front": "what is the Dunlop traction for?", "back": "o treat, align, and immobilize severely displaced or unstable supracondylar fractures of the humerus (elbow fractures) in children." },
    { "front": "A temporary immobilizing device which is made up of gypsum silfate redered unhydrous by calcination", "back": "Plaster cast" }
  ]
}
